<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<service_def name="VelocityStateSensor" id="urn:jaus:jss:mobility:VelocityStateSensor" version="1.0" xmlns="urn:jaus:jsidl:1.0" xmlns:ns1="urn:jaus:jsidl:1.1">
  <description>
    The Velocity State Sensor has the responsibility of reporting the instantaneous velocity of the platform.  
    The velocity state of a rigid body is defined as the set of parameters that are necessary to calculate 
    he velocity of any point in that rigid body.  Six parameters are required to specify a velocity state of a 
    rigid body in terms of some fixed reference coordinate system.  The first three parameters represent 
    the velocity components of a point in the rigid body that is coincident with the origin of the fixed reference.  
    The second three components represent the instantaneous angular velocity components.  It is possible 
    to represent the six velocity state parameters as a screw, about which the rigid body is rotating and 
    translating along at that instant.
    
    The reference frame for the velocity state sensor component is selected as a fixed coordinate system 
    that at this instant is co-located with and aligned with the vehicle or system coordinate system.  Thus the 
    message data ‘velocity x’, ‘velocity y’, and ‘velocity z’ represents the current velocity of the subsystem’s 
    control point at this instant.  For example if ‘velocity x’ has a value of 3 m/sec and ‘velocity y’ and ‘velocity z’ 
    are zero, then the vehicle is moving in the forward direction at a velocity of 3 m/sec.  The message data 
    ‘omega x’, ‘omega y’, and ‘omega z’ represent the actual rate of change of orientation or angular velocity 
    of the vehicle about its coordinate axes.
  </description>
  <assumptions>Messages may be delayed, lost or reordered.</assumptions>
  <references>
    <inherits_from name="events" id="urn:jaus:jss:core:Events" version="1.0"/>
  </references>
  <declared_type_set name="Types">
    <declared_type_set_ref name="mobility" id="urn:jaus:jss:mobility:MessageSet" version="1.0"/>
  </declared_type_set>
  <message_set>
    <input_set>
      <declared_message_def name="QueryVelocityState" declared_type_ref="mobility.queryClass.QueryVelocityState"/>
    </input_set>
    <output_set>
      <declared_message_def name="ReportVelocityState" declared_type_ref="mobility.informClass.ReportVelocityState"/>
    </output_set>
  </message_set>
  <internal_events_set/>
  <protocol_behavior>
    <start state_machine_name="events.transport.ReceiveFSM"
      state_name="Receiving.Ready"/>
    <state_machine name="events.transport.ReceiveFSM" 
        interpretation="extending ReceiveFSM of base service (transport)">
      <state name="Receiving" initial_state="Ready" interpretation="redefine state in order to extend">
        <state name="Ready" interpretation="redefine state in order to extend">
              <default_state>
                <transition name="events.transport.Receive">
                  <parameter type="QueryVelocityState" value="msg" interpretation="enveloped query velocity
                    state message"/>
                  <parameter type="Receive.Body.ReceiveRec" value="transportData" interpretation="transport data"/>
                  <simple/>
                  <action name="events.transport.Send" interpretation="Send a Report
                    Velocity State message">
                    <argument value=" 'ReportVelocityState' "/>
                    <argument value="transportData"/>
                  </action>
                </transition>
              </default_state>
        </state>
      </state>
    </state_machine>
  </protocol_behavior>
</service_def>
